So in this first case, we have three columns, student name, teacher name, and
因此 在第一种情况下 我们有三列 学生姓名、教师姓名和
the student's grade.
学生的成绩
One of the rules for normalization is that we have to have a unique key,
规范化的规则之一就是 我们必须有一个唯一键
that says what each row is about, but names aren't unique.
描述了每一行的意义 但名字不是唯一的
If we have two students named Jake Smith, or Pavel Ivanov, or
如果我们有两个学生都叫 Jake Smith 或 Pavel Ivanov
something else, this isn't going to do very well.
或别的什么 这不好
Also, if a student is taking two courses taught by the same teacher like,
同样 如果一个学生学的两门课是由同一个老师教的
maybe a CS and a math course.
比如 CS 或数学课
We'll have problems there, too.
我们也会遇到问题
So this is not normalized.
因此这也不是规范化
Over here, we also have a single table.
这边 我们也有一个表格
Here we've given each student a unique id number.
我们给每个学生一个唯一的 ID 号
And we're also using a unique id for
我们对课程也使用唯一的 ID
courses, instead of just the teacher's name.
而不是只对老师的姓名这样做
But, we're storing facts that don't have to do with each other in the same table.
但是 我们存储信息的表格之间并不一定要有什么关系
Like student 23 is always Jake Smith, regardless of what course he's taking.
比如23号学生始终都是 Jake Smith 不论他学的是什么课
This really ought to be split into two tables, so this is also not normalized.
实际上这应该分成两个表格 因此这也不是规范化
And splitting it into two tables,
把它分成两个表格
is exactly what we've done in this third group.
这个操作我们在第三组中已经完成了
One table that gives the relationship between each student id and their name.
一个表格给出了每个学生 ID 与他们姓名之间的关系
And the other gives the grade for each course they take.
另一个给出了学生学习的每一门课程的成绩
If all we know is a student's name,
如果我们只知道学生的姓名
we can join this against that to find their courses.
我们可以依照那个表格对这个表格进行连接 找到他们所学的课程
But, if there are two students with the same name, we will get both.
但是 如果有两个同名的学生我们会得到两个
Nonetheless, this is normalized.
不管怎样 这是规范化
And the fourth group, the only difference between this one and
第四组 这个表格与那个表格之间唯一的不同就是
that one, is that here, we're also keeping track of students' birth dates.
还记录了学生的出生日期
But a person only has one birth date.
但一个人只有一个出生日期
And the birth date, doesn't have anything to do with their grades.
而出生日期与学生的成绩没有任何关系
So adding this column to this table,
因此在这个表格中添加这一列
doesn't make this any less normalized than this one.
并不会让这个表格的规范化程度比这个差
So this and this, are both normalized.
因此这个和这个都是规范化的